

## Ruud van Falier

Born January 31st 1984 in 's-Hertogenbosch, The Netherlands

Address Van Reysstraat 99 5213 HA 's-Hertogenbosch Contact +31 (0)6 51 44 73 63 ruud@dottech.nl

## Introduction

Ruud started programming as an 11-year-old kid with QBasic and quickly moved on to Pascal and later C++, creating all kinds of software and games on the way. After being introduced to the internet in 1996, it didn't take long for his first freelance web projects to be realized. Before even turning 17, he was working full-time as a web developer for an internet company.

Today, over twelve years later, Ruud has evolved into a multidisciplinary software engineer with a focus on web development, mostly on Microsoft platforms.

Besides being a software engineer, he is also running ParTech IT; a contracting agency that specializes exclusively in the secondment and training of Sitecore specialists.

Together with his business partner, who is also a very skilled software engineer, they pass on their experience to their employees so they are able to provide more customers with their high quality services.

## Specialism and relevant experience

#### 1. Specialized in

#### Technique Since ASP.NET (1.1 - 4.5)2003 2003 Sitecore (MVP since 2013, 2004 see section Awards) MS-SQL 2001 HTML / CSS 1998 JavaScript 1998 2006 jQuery

#### 2. Highly experienced in

Technique	Since	Technique
MVC.NET	2009	Lucene.NET
PHP	2000	iOS Developr
C++	1999	(Objective C)
MySQL	2000	EPiServer
NHibernate	2010	Drupal
IIS	2000	Smartsite
		Game develo

#### 3. Experience with

Technique	Since
Lucene.NET	2012
iOS Development	2011
(Objective C)	
EPiServer	2013
Drupal	2009
Smartsite	2003
Game development	1995

#### Tools that are frequently used by Ruud:

- Visual Studio 2012 / 2010
- dotPeek / Reflector
- FireBug
- Versioncontrol: Git, SVN, TFS
- Notepad++
- TeamCity
- SoapUI

- Total Commander
- SQL Server Management Studio
- Sitecore Rocks
- Photoshop
- StyleCop

## **Work Experience**

January 2012 until now

## Managing Director Senior Sitecore / .NET Consultant

at ParTech IT B.V.

ParTech is the only dutch contracting agency that specializes exclusively on secondment and training of Sitecore developers and consultants. Together with his business partner Ruud is responsible for the company's management and he also work as a developer and consultant himself.

At ParTech IT Ruud has worked for:

- eFocus (full-service internet agency)
- Caesar Groep

August 2011 until now

#### **Freelance Software Engineer**

DotTech B.V.

After Stribe was shut down, Ruud started working as freelance software engineer under the name DotTech. Companies can hire him for any of his skills, but he specializes in Sitecore and .NET and that's what he is usually asked for.

During the first year he has worked for:

- eFocus (full-service internet agency)
- Computer Futures
- Mariagerfjord Kommune (Denmark)
- Frontmedia (UK)
- Digital material
- A2Concepts

January 2010 until July 2011

# Managing Director / Senior Software Engineer at Stribe B.V.

Stribe was an internet startup that Ruud started together with a good friend and the help of an investor. They developed a platform for affiliate-feed-driven websites with a social touch and presented it as a social shopping platform. Although technically the project was a big success, the concept did not have much success commercially and they were forced to shut down.

During this period Ruud has worked together with a development team in Minsk, Belarus. It has taught him a lot about outsourcing projects to eastern Europe which has been a good experience that is being used now by ParTech IT.

January 2003 until January 2010

## Senior Software Engineer

at Colours B.V., LECTRIC Group

Ruud has worked for Colours for 7 years, under the following function descriptions:

#### 2003 - 2005: Software Engineer

During this period Ruud started out using a wide variety of techniques and started focusing more on Smartsite along the way. He worked on projects for customers including: Camping, VNG, Bovag, Unique, Thema, ISES, among others.

2005 - 2008: Senior Software Engineer (Smartsite) / Team Lead During this period Ruud was the team lead for the development team that worked exclusively on projects based on the Smartsite CMS. His team was responsible for development and support for customers including: De Efteling, 9292ov, Gemeente Purmerend, Schouten & Nelissen, Univé, Hypotheekshop, among others.

#### 2008 - 2010 : Senior Software Engineer (Sitecore)

During this period Ruud has worked exclusively on projects based on the Sitecore CMS and he was responsible for development and support for customers including: RET, KPC Group, FCB, LECTRIC Opleidingen, among others.

October 2002 until December 2002

#### PHP engineer

at Solid Technologies

A short period during which Ruud developed small websites using PHP. This company was started by a few old colleagues from Switchworld and unfortunately went bankrupt soon after Ruud could join them.

October 2000 until October 2002

#### ASP engineer / Web Designer

at Switchworld B.V.

Switchworld was a company that created amusement websites with paid access and was among the biggest (if not, the biggest) of their kind in the Netherlands.

In Ruud his early Switchworld days, he started out as a web designer who also converted the designs to HTML and quickly evolved into an ASP engineer with the responsibility of extending and maintaining the payment platform which was the core business for this company.

1999 until 2000

#### PHP engineer

at LOGO Grafisch Ontwerp

During this period Ruud was regularly hired by this graphic design company to help them develop their PHP-driven websites for customers.

## **Training and exams**

2008 Sitecore 6 - Certified Web Developer
Training and examination by Sitecore

2007 Job Evaluation Conversations and Assessment Interviews

Training by Schouten & Nelissen

2007 Time Management

Training by Schouten & Nelissen

2005 - 2006 Microsoft Certified Application Developer

• 70-315: Developing web applications with C#

70-316: Developing Windows-based applications with C#

70-320: Developing XML web services and server components with C#

2005 Sitecore 4 - Certified Developer

Training and examination by Sitecore

2003 - 2007 Smartsite training

Smartsite 4.5 - Site Building
 Smartsite 5 - Site Management
 Smartsite 5 - Site Building

Smartsite 5 - Enterprise Site Building
 Smartsite 5.1 - Advanced Site Building
 Smartsite Content Intelligence Module

Smartsite Aggregated Search

2003 C# .NET - basic training

8 nights of in-company training

2002 Active Server Pages

Training and examination by Sitecore

## **Education**

2000 - 2001 Computer Engineering (Technische Informatica) MBO

Koning Willem I college, 's-Hertogenbosch (no diploma)

1998 - 2000 MAVO (level D)

d'Oultremontcollega, Vlijmen (graduated)

Subjects:

Economics

Mathematics

Physics

Dutch

English

German

1996 – 1998 **VWO** 

d'Oultremontcollega, Vlijmen (no diploma)

## **Awards**

2013 In February 2013 Ruud was elected Sitecore MVP (Most Valued Professional).

http://www.sitecore.net/Company/News/Press-releases/2013/02/Sitecore-MVPs.aspx

## **Online references**

StackOverflow Ruud is an active member of StackOverflow where he helps other developers with (mostly)

Sitecore related questions:

http://stackoverflow.com/users/181142/ruud-van-falier

ParTech IT blog Ruud regulary publishes blog posts related to Sitecore on the ParTech IT website:

http://www.partechit.nl/nl/blog

**DotTech blog** Before Ruud started blogging on the ParTech website, he used to publish technical posts on

his personal blog. That is where you can find his older publications:

http://ruuddottech.blogspot.nl/

**GitHub** Some of Ruud's hobby projects are publicly available on GitHub:

https://github.com/Stribe

## Offline references

Company eFocus

**Relation** Ruud has worked here as a freelance *Senior Sitecore / .NET developer* for over a year.

Contact Erik Ferweda

Branch manager

http://nl.linkedin.com/in/eferweda

erik.ferweda@efocus.nl +31 (0)6 - 47 14 78 59

**Company** Caesar Group

**Relation** Ruud was the *lead Sitecore / .NET developer* on one of their projects.

**Contact** Michiel de Sain

Manager

http://nl.linkedin.com/in/micheldesain

m.sain@caesar.nl

**Company** Colours

**Relation** (see work experience)

**Contact** Paul Hinze

Managing director (back then)

http://nl.linkedin.com/pub/paul-hinze/0/b1b/b7a

p.hinze@lectric.nl

+31 (0)73 - 68 11 004 (reception)